hey guys let's visualize sine squared
plus cosine squared equals 1. this right
here is the graph for sine of x and this
red one is sine squared of x you'll
notice how everywhere where the sine is
negative the sine squared becomes
positive and you can tell here in the
positive area that the shape of the
graph changes a little bit as well so
the sine squared of pi over two is equal
to one we can tell that because the
height of the graph is one at x equals
pi over two we can shade from the x-axis
to the height of the sine squared of x
graph the reason that's nice is because
if i shift it upwards it's no longer the
height on the y-axis that tells me the
function value is the height of the
shading at each point that tells me the
function value i could even turn upside
down like this and it really wouldn't
matter here at x equals pi over 2 we can
see that this height is still 1. next we
can look at the graph of cosine of x and
then in blue here we have cosine squared
of x let's get rid of this cosine of x a
shape between the x-axis and the y-axis
so that the height of the shaded area
gives us the function value and now
let's bring down our sine squared of x
and you see they fit together perfectly
and that gives us sine squared plus
cosine squared is equal to one how
exciting